YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 5. International Work
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. PROJECTS AND PROGRAMS
  - World Mutual Service (World Fellowship)
    - History, 1956-73 (includes YWCA World Mutual Service: Common Quest by Marion O. Robinson, 1973) (Box 319, Folder 2)
    - Publications and resource kits for member associations, [see also Publications-Periodicals-World Connections]
      - General
        - 1910-26, 1930-40, 1946-57, 1961-69 (Box 319, Folder 3-8)
        - 1970-90, n.d. (Box 320, Folder 1)
      - World Week of Prayer, 1907-74 (Box 320, Folder 2)
    - "World Fellowship Ahoy!": cartoon from The Woman's Press, Sep 1927 (Box 320, Folder 3)
  - World YWCA cooperation
    - Committee to consider priorities for World YWCA in future (Palmer letter 2/74), 1974 (Box 320, Folder 4)
    - Ruth Sovik: correspondence, 1983-85 (Box 320, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous lists, memos, and printed materials, (1920), 1938, 1967-98 (Box 320, Folder 6)
- SERIES V. PUBLICATIONS
  - Pamphlets, brochures, flyers, and other printed materials
    - General, 1907-43, 1955, n.d. (Box 320, Folder 7-10)
    - Charts and maps, 1911-88, n.d., [see also Oversize materials] (Box 320, Folder 11)
    - Finances, 1914-20 (Box 320, Folder 12)
    - Statistics, 1921, 1924-28, 1944, 1959-60 (Box 320, Folder 13)
    - World War I: Making the World Safe for Women, (1917)Needs the World Over, (1918)and Working and Praying Together (1918) (Box 320, Folder 14)
  - Periodicals/newsletters
    - "Association Sidelights," 1931 (Box 320, Folder 15)
    - "The F.D. D.E.W. Line," 1973-74 (Box 320, Folder 16)
    - Foreign Exchange: News from Abroad with Suggestions for World Fellowship Program, 1939-41 (Box 321, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Facts, 1925-30/31; World Cooperation, 1932/33 (Box 321, Folder 2-3)
    - "Foreign News Items," (1914)-20 (Box 321, Folder 4-5)
    - "Foreign Mail," 1929-34 (includes one issue of "International Radiogram, 1926) (Box 321, Folder 6)
    - "Global Briefs," 1996-98 (Box 321, Folder 7)
    - Newsletter to the staff abroad, 1920-35 (Box 321, Folder 8-9)
    - Under a Foreign Stamp, 1938-39 (Box 322, Folder 1)
    - World Connections, 1989-92 (Box 322, Folder 2-3)
    - World Cooperation, [see Foreign Facts]
    - World Wise, 1980 (Box 322, Folder 4)
- SERIES VI. COUNTRIES AND REGIONS
  - Scrapbooks: articles, brochures, clippings, correspondence, papers, reports, 1947-71
    - Africa - British Honduras (Box 322, Folder 5)
    - Burma - Columbia (Box 322, Folder 6)
    - Cyprus - Great Britain (Box 322, Folder 7)
    - Greece - India (Box 322, Folder 8)
    - Italy - Jordan (Box 323, Folder 1)
    - Kenya (Box 323, Folder 2)
    - Korea (Box 323, Folder 3)
    - Latin America - Madagascar (Box 323, Folder 4)
    - Malaysia - Nigeria (Box 323, Folder 5)
    - Organismo Tecnico (Training Project for Latin America) - Peru (Box 323, Folder 6)
    - Philippines (Box 323, Folder 7)
    - Puerto Rico - South Africa (Box 323, Folder 8)
    - Surinam - Taipei (Box 324, Folder 1)
    - Tanzania - Trinidad and Tobago (Box 324, Folder 2)
    - Turkey - Uganda (Box 324, Folder 3)
    - United States - Zambia (Box 324, Folder 4)
    - "I.D. Historical Record: Europe and Africa," 1921, 1946-1971
      - Europe - Italy (Box 324, Folder 5)
      - Africa - Liberia (Box 324, Folder 6)
      - Nigeria - Uganda (Box 324, Folder 7)
  - International Survey of YMCA and YWCA
    - Minutes, reports, and correspondence
      - 1927-29 (Box 324, Folder 8-9)
      - 1930-33 (Box 325, Folder 1-2)
    - Argentina: Survey of the YMCA in Argentina, 1929: Survey of the YWCA in Argentina, n.d. (Box 325, Folder 3)
    - Chile, Brazil, and Uruguay: The Report of the International Survey on the YMCA and the YWCA in Chile; Survey of the YMCA and the YWCA in Brazil; and Survey of the Young Men's Christian Associations and the Young Women's Christian Associations: Findings of the National Commission for Uruguay (all undated) (Box 325, Folder 4)
    - China
      - A Study of the YWCA of China, 1890-1930 (typescript) (Box 325)
        - Vol. 1 (Box 325, Folder 5)
        - Vol. 2 (Box 325, Folder 6)
      - A Study of the Y.W.C.A. of China, 1891-1930 (printed pamphlet) (Box 325, Folder 7)
      - [YMCA study, Vol. 2? (starts with Chapter IV, pg. 108)] (Box 326, Folder 1)
    - Egypt: Survey of the YMCA in Egypt,n.d.
      - Vol. 1 (Box 326, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 2 (Box 326, Folder 3)
    - Estonia: Report of the YMCA and the YWCA in Esthonia, (1920-30) (Box 326, Folder 4)
    - Greece: Report on the Survey of the Work of the Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association of Greece by Gregory Papamichael, May 1930 (Box 326, Folder 5)
    - India
      - Statistical charts, circa 1930 (Box 327, Folder 1)
      - A Study of the YWCA of India, Burma, and Ceylon, (1929-30) (Box 327, Folder 2)
      - A Study of the YMCA of India, Burma, and Ceylon, Vols. 1-3 (Box 327, Folder 3-4)
    - Japan
      - Survey of the YMCA and YWCA in Japan, 1930, parts 1-4 (Box 327, Folder 5-8)
      - The Survey of the Work of the Young Men's and Young Women's Christian Associations: Report of Conclusions, Nov 1930 (Box 328, Folder 1)
    - Korea: Survey of the Young Men's Christian Association and the Young Women's Christian Association of Korea, July 1930 (Box 328, Folder 2)
    - Latin America
      - International Survey (South America), 1928: local association summaries (Box 328, Folder 3)
      - Latin America YMCA and YWCA, 1930: Area Report on Latin America by Margaret K. Strong and C.E. Silcox, parts 1 and 2 (Box 328, Folder 4-5)
    - Latvia: Survey of the YMCA and the YWCA in Latvia, (1930) (Box 328, Folder 6)
    - Mexico: Survey of the YMCA and the YWCA in Mexico, (1930) (Box 328, Folder 7)
    - Palestine: The Report of the Survey in Palestine, (1930) (Box 328, Folder 8)
    - Philippines: [Study, 1930], parts 1 and 2 (Box 329, Folder 1-2)
    - Russia: Survey of the North American YMCA Service to Russians in Europe, 1930, parts 1 and 2 (Box 329, Folder 3-4)
    - South Africa: Report of the Young Men's Christian Association in South Africa by George Edmund Haynes, (1930) (Box 329, Folder 5)
    - Syria: Report of the YWCA in Syria, (1930) (Box 329, Folder 6)
    - Turkey
      - YWCA: Report of the Service Centers, Istanbul, Turkey, November 1929 - June 1930
        - Part 1 (Box 329, Folder 7)
        - Part 2 (Box 330, Folder 1)
      - Survey Commission Report of the Young Men's Christian Association, Istanbul, Turkey, June 14, 1930, parts 1 and 2 (Box 330, Folder 2-3)
  - Section Chairmen: minutes, 1922-29 (Box 330, Folder 4-6)
  - Country files, A-Z
    - Argentina: publications, 1906-circa 1926, n.d. (Box 330, Folder 7)
    - Armenia, [see Near East]
    - Bahamas: report and correspondence (Ruth Soumah), 1977, 1979 (Box 330, Folder 8)
    - Baltic States, (circa 1924), [see also Estonia] (Box 330, Folder 9)
    - Botswana: reports (Ruth Soumah), 1976, 1978-79 (Box 330, Folder 10)
    - Brazil: reports, 1923, circa 1926, 1928 (Box 330, Folder 11)
    - Burma, [see India]
    - Ceylon, [see India]
    - Chile: printed materials and speech notes [?], 1960, 1964, n.d. (Box 330, Folder 12)
    - China
      - Studies, papers, and speeches on status of women (Box 331, Folder 1)
        - "Report on China" by Ernestine I. Friedmann, July 1920; "A Talk Given By Mrs. H.C. Mei, Vice-President of the National Committee of the Y.W.C.A of China at a Meeting Given in Shanghai in December 1920;" "Women and the Church" by Ruth Cheng, 14 Jul 1922; "The Women's Rights Movement in China" by Zung Wei Tsung, Sep 1922; "The New Woman of China" (radio talk), Nov 1924; "Changing Leadership: A study based on reports from American mission stations regarding the place of women in national churches" by Katherine E. Vaughn, June 1926; "China's New Law of Family Relations" by Kuo Min (National Committee Y.W.C.A. News Service), 4 Dec 1930; "New Family Relations in China (Special to the N.C.D.N?)," Jul 1931; "Status of Women in China" (preliminary draft) prepared under the auspices of the International Education Commission of the National Committee of the YWCA of China, 1939; "With Centuries Behind It.. .China in Transition and the Y.W.C.A. Serving Her" by Mrs. Emmett C. Barr, (late 1930s); "Women's Organizations During These Five Years" by Lily K. Haass, copied 30 Nov 1943 1920-1943 (Box 331)
        - The Role of the YWCA in the Development of the Chinese Women's Movement, 1890-1927 by Alison R. Drucker, 1979 (Box 331, Folder 2)
      - China Section
        - Minutes, 1920-21 (Box 331, Folder 3)
      - Staff reports
        - 1917-22, n.d
          - Anderson, Elsie (Canton); Beers, Miriam (Shanghai); Braden, Elvira M. (Nanking); Brooks, Rachel (Peking); Brown, Florence (South China, Shanghai); Carter, Hester (Shanghai); Coppock, Grace (General Secretary); Danuser, Maybelle (Shanghai); Davis, Nellie (Nanking Language School); Derry, Evelyn (Tientsin); Dodge, Adelia (Canton); Durfee, Elizabeth (Nanking); Eddy, Katherine Willard (Shangai); Forbes, Erma (Peking); Fraser, Ruth (Chengtu); Grabill, Ada (Shanghai); Haass, Lily K. (Peking); Hartley, Ethel (Hangchow); Holmes, Alice (Peking); Hoople, Ruth (Mukden); Howes, Ruth; Huie, Alice and Caroline (Shanghai); Job, Martha (Shanghai); Kitchin, Eleanor (Shanghai); Lowry, Genevieve (Hangchow); Mack, Margaret (Hangchow); MacKinlay, Margaret (Shanghai); March, Carolyn (Tientsin); Myers, Hazel (Peking) (Box 331, Folder 4)
          - Neely, Charlotte (Foochow); Peking Union Language School students; Rietveld, Harriet (Shanghai); Russell, Maud (Changsha); Sargent, Clara (Shanghai); Sawyer, Edith O. (Shanghai); Scott, Helen (Foochow); Seesholtz, Anna G. (Student Dept., Shanghai); Severin, Theresa (Peking); Smith, Harriet (Chengtu); Steel-Brooke, Gertrude (Foochow); Steinbeck, Grace C. (Foochow); Streeter, Mary E. (Peking Language School); Swann, Nancy Lee (Tsinan); Thoburn, Helen (China National Committee); Vance, Catherine ;Vaughn, Katharine E. (Canton); Ward, Jane (Shanghai); Wells, Edith (Tientsin); White, Ruth (Tientsin); Williams, Katharine (Peking); Willis, Lina (Shanghai); Willis, Mary (Canton) (Box 331, Folder 5)
        - 1925-31: Miscellaneous from Helen Thoburn, Eleanor MacNeil, Eleanor Hinder, and Ting Shu-Ching (Box 331, Folder 6)
        - 1926-30: Ella Bennett (Mukden) (Box 331, Folder 7)
      - Girls work in Szechwan (Mildred Owen): plans, program, and lists, 1941, n.d. (Box 331, Folder 8)
      - National Committee of China
        - Minutes, 1919-26 (Box 331, Folder 9-10)
        - Publication: The Green Year, The Y.W.C.A. Magazine, Oct 1923, [missing all but cover and first 2 pages] (Box 331, Folder 11)
      - Publications
        - YWCA of the USA
          - Pamphlets and brochures
            - 1908-19 (Box 331, Folder 12)
            - n.d. (Box 332, Folder 1)
          - Articles, 1914-18, 1931, 1994 (Box 332, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous printed materials by others or unidentified, 1908-18, 1929-32, 1973, 1985, 1987, n.d. (Box 332, Folder 3)
      - Publicity: correspondence, papers, press releases, and reports, 1925-50 (Box 332, Folder 4-7)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - History
        - Correspondence, 1991-92 (Box 332, Folder 8)
        - "A Gleam in the Eye of the Overseas Committee: The YWCA in Czechoslovakia," 1991: paper, printed research materials, and notes, 1920-91 (Box 332, Folder 9)
      - Studies
        - "The Occupations of Women in Greater Prague" by Alpha Buse, Vol. VI. Social Survey of Prague (Published by the Ministry of Social Welfare, Prague) 1920, parts 1 and 2 (Box 332, Folder 10-11)
        - "Recreation Survey of Prague" by Anne Rylance Smith, The Prague Social Welfare Survey, Vol. IV. (published by the Ministry of Social Welfare, Prague), 1920 (Box 332, Folder 12)
      - Constitution, bylaws, and policies, 1919-22 (Box 332, Folder 13)
      - Staff reports
        - 1919-23: Bell, Vesper (Finance Dept., National Board); Caldwell, Anne (Finance Secretary); Clark, Faith (Bratislava) (Box 332, Folder 14)
        - Crawford, Ruth (Prague), 1919-1920 (Box 332, Folder 15-16)
        - Duthie, Eva (Recreation Dept./Club Dept., Prague); Food Service/Home Economics Dept. (Mabel McBride and Katharine H. Schoonover); Geary, Marjorie (Recreation Secretary, Prague); Hurlburt, Mary; Pauliny, Marina (Bratislava) (Box 333, Folder 1)
        - Prudden, Elinor (General Secretary) (Box 333, Folder 2)
        - Turner, Mabel (City Secretary, Prague); and Vashek, Anna (Liaison, Prague) (Box 333, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1919-50 (Box 333, Folder 4-8)
      - Miscellaneous reports, speeches, and publications, 1921-26, 1936-39, 1946-48 (Box 333, Folder 9)
      - Publicity: correspondence and reports, 1946-48 (Box 333, Folder 10)
      - Student Department and YWCA/YMCA cooperation, 1919-21 (Box 333, Folder 11)
    - Egypt
      - Request for secretary in Cairo: correspondence, 1917-21 (Box 333, Folder 12)
      - A Camel Trip to Cairo: a Program on Egypt by Helen L. Willcox (The Womans Press) 1920 (Box 333, Folder 13)
    - Estonia: The Young Women's Christian Association in Estonia: a Study in the Transplanting of an Institution by Lois Diehl (Master's thesis, University of Chicago) 1934, [see also Baltic States] (Box 333, Folder 14)
    - Europe Section: minutes, 1920-22 (Box 334, Folder 1)
    - France: letter, 1946 (Box 334, Folder 2)
    - India, Burma, and Ceylon
      - India Section
        - Purpose and policies, n.d. (Box 334, Folder 3)
        - Minutes, 1920-21 (Box 334, Folder 4)
        - Reports, 1915-21
          - Alexander, Anna (Ceylon), 1917; Carswell, Rena (Bombay), 1916; Cowdrey, Ruth (Bombay), 1917; Cron, Beatrice (Calcutta), 1915-17; Denison, Florence (Simla and Lahore), 1915-17; Dennison, Martha (Jubbulpore), 1920-21; Downey, Martha (Madras), 1915-20; Hartwell, Stephenia (Calcutta), 1920-21; Lamb, Anne O. (Lahore), 1915-16 (Box 334, Folder 5)
          - Lang, Florence B. (Bombay), 1915-16; Melcher, Margery (Madras), 1915-17; Radford, Laura (Singapore), 1915-16; Rutherford, Mary (Singapore, Simla and Calcutta), 1915-17, 1921; Shields, Alice (Bombay), 1915-17; Terry, Eva (Rangoon), 1920-21; Whealdon, Martha (Bombay), 1915-17; Wilson, Elizabeth (Calcutta), 1920-21; Wilson, Margaret N. (Madras), 1921; Withers, Myra (Bombay), 1915-17 (Box 334, Folder 6)
      - Anne Guthrie: correspondence, 1939-43 (Box 334, Folder 7)
      - India National Committee
        - Minutes
          - 1924-Apr 1926 (Box 334, Folder 8-9)
          - Jul 1926-1927 (Box 335, Folder 1-3)
        - Publications, 1923, circa 1966, 1975 (Box 335, Folder 4)
      - Publications
        - YWCA of the USA, 1913-14, 1919, 1926, 1950, n.d. (Box 335, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 335, Folder 6)
    - Japan
      - Study: "Institutional Management Survey, Tokyo Y.W.C.A," Nov 1937 (Box 335, Folder 7)
      - Japan Section
        - Purpose, principles, etc., n.d. and minutes, 1920-21, 1924 (Box 335, Folder 8)
        - Reports 1918-1921
          - Allchin, Agnes (Yokohama), 1918; Allen, Carolyn E. (Tokyo), 1920-21; Allen, Eleanor (Osaka), 1920; Armstrong, Clare (Tokyo), 1920-21; Baker, Mary C. (Yokohama),1915, 1918-19; Best, Blanche (Tokyo), 1920 (Box 335, Folder 9)
          - Birdsall, Anna P. (Kyoto), 1920-21; Chambers, Lillian (Kyoto), 1919; Crawford, Inez (Osaka), 1917; Dunning, Elizabeth (Tokyo), 1920-21; Emerson, Ruth (Tokyo), 1916; Ferris, Sara D. (Tokyo), 1920-21; Fonda, Ethel (Tokyo), 1917-18; Gunter, Mamie E. (Tokyo), 1916-17 (Box 335, Folder 10)
          - Hard, Clara Taylor (Osaka), 1916-20; Jordan, Edith Allen (Yokohama), 1921; Lacy, Lelia (or Leila?) Lyle (Tokyo), 1920-21; Matthew, Margaret (Tokyo), 1916-18; McGregor, Grace (Tokyo), 1920-21; Nixon, Esther (Tokyo), 1917-18; Page, Mary (Tokyo), 1915-21 (Box 335, Folder 11)
          - Ragan, Ruth (Tokyo), 1915-16, 1920-21; Scott, Jane N. (Tokyo), 1920; Topping, Helen F. (Kobe), 1916, 1918-21; Verry, Hazel (Yokohama), 1920; Wiser, Edna M. (Tokyo), 1920-21; Woods, Margaret W. (Tokyo), 1921 (Box 336, Folder 1)
          - Special reports of Charlotte Adams, Apr 1919 - Apr 1920 (Box 336, Folder 2)
        - Publicity
          - Correspondence, reports, and printed materials, 1929, 1946-50, 1982, n.d. (Box 336, Folder 3)
          - "A Year in the United States" by Mizuho Kunugi, (1951) (Box 336, Folder 4)
        - Publications
          - National Association, 1907?-1948, n.d. (Box 336, Folder 5)
          - YWCA of Japan and miscellaneous other, 1916-95, n.d. (Box 336, Folder 6)
    - Jordan: publications, 1961, n.d. (Box 336, Folder 7)
    - Korea
      - Publicity: history, diary excerpt, correspondence, reports, clippings, and speeches, 1946-50, 1962 (Box 336, Folder 8)
      - Publications of YWCA of Korea, 1988, 1991 (Box 336, Folder 9)
    - Latin America
      - Latin American Section: minutes, 1920-28 (Box 336, Folder 10)
      - Staff reports
        - 1915-16: Breed, Persis; Cortez, Elisa; Rouse, Ruth; Sheppard, Irene (Box 336, Folder 11)
        - 1920-21: Batty, E. Jean; Brininstool, Bessie; Chapin, Emma; Cortez, Elisa; Davidson, Patricia; Drake, Frances; Heiskell, Mary; King, Myrth; McFarland, Elizabeth; Miller, Bernice; Robertson, Margaret; Russell, Mary; Sheldon, Ruth; Stokely, Anna May (Box 336, Folder 12)
        - Anne Guthrie
          - Reports, 1930-34 (Box 336, Folder 13)
          - Correspondence, 1930-33 (Box 336, Folder 14)
        - Committees
          - Continental Committee for Latin America (Comision Continental de la Asociacion Christiana Feminina): minutes, 1920-24 (Box 337, Folder 1)
          - Committee on Cooperation in Latin America: minutes, 1916-25 (Box 337, Folder 2)
        - Latin American consultant, 1983-84 (Box 337, Folder 3)
        - Publications and other printed materials
          - YWCA of the USA, 1907-29, n.d. (Box 337, Folder 4)
          - Miscellaneous, 1935, 1961, 1967 (Box 337, Folder 5)
          - Unidentified notes [speeches?]: typescripts, n.d. (Box 337, Folder 6)
    - Lebanon
      - Study: "The Status of Women in Lebanon, a Sample Study Drawn by the Public Affairs Committee of the Y.W.C.A. of Lebanon," 1949 (Box 337, Folder 7)
      - Publicity: correspondence and reports
        - 1934-57 (Box 337, Folder 8)
        - 1967-79 (includes brochure for YWCA refugee services) (Box 337, Folder 9)
      - Publications: YWCA of Lebanon and miscellaneous other, 1948, 1983-91 (Box 337, Folder 10)
    - Liberia: publicity, including correspondence and reports, 1948-50 (Box 337, Folder 11)
    - Mexico
      - Correspondence and reports, 1963-86, n.d. (Box 337, Folder 12)
      - Publications: brochures, 1940, and article, 1938 (Box 337, Folder 13)
    - Near East: publications, (1919), n.d. (Box 337, Folder 14)
    - Oriental Section: minutes, 1921-22 (Box 337, Folder 15)
    - Philippines
      - Correspondence and reports
        - Anne Guthrie
          - 1933-May 1935 (Box 337, Folder 16)
          - Jun 1935-40 (Box 338, Folder 1-3)
        - Miscellaneous, 1946-47, 1949, 1968 (Box 338, Folder 4)
      - Publications, 1946, 1949, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 5)
      - "Peace Book Entries," YWCA Leadership Development Center, Phoenix, n.d. (circa 1980s?) (Box 338, Folder 6)
    - Poland: typescript of "A Post-War Y.W.C.A. Project in Poland" by Sarah S. Lyon, 1975 (Box 338, Folder 7)
    - Puerto Rico
      - Correspondence and reports (Lena York Roth, Guadalupe Colon, Frances Munn, and Evelyn Dean), 1945-50 (Box 338, Folder 8)
      - Publications
        - Newsletters, article, brochures and programs, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 9)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 10)
    - Romania: correspondence
      - Margaretta Pruitianna Voiculescu and Lucy Pray (includes photographs), 1922-25, 1967, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 11)
      - "Helen" to family (typescript), 1922-23 (Box 338, Folder 12)
    - Russia: article from War Work Bulletin 54, 3 Jan 1919 re: Russian staff (Box 338, Folder 13)
    - South Africa: letter and memos re: Connie NGCABA, Joyce, Seroke, Jane Phakathi, Vesta Smith, and Phumzile Mlambo-Ngcuka, and Bulelani Ngcuka, 1987-88 (Box 338, Folder 14)
    - Thailand: reports and correspondence, 1947-48 (Box 338, Folder 15)
    - Taiwan: Taipei YWCA brochures and annual reports, 1948-93 (Box 338, Folder 16)
    - Turkey
      - History, 1980, 1985, 1987, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 17)
      - Report by Ruth Woodsmall, 1925, and miscellaneous correspondence, 1961-62, 1990-91 (Box 338, Folder 18)
      - Amerikan Lisan ve San'at Dersanesi (American Girls Service Center), Istanbul
        - Deed, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 19)
        - Rules and regulations, 1945; By-laws, 1960 (Box 338, Folder 20)
        - 1948 Ford: legal documents and correspondence, 1947 (Box 338, Folder 21)
        - American Liaison Committee (Betty Jo Swayze file)
          - Minutes, reports and correspondence, 1971-87, n.d. (Box 338, Folder 22)
          - Financial materials, 1950, 1975-88 (Box 338, Folder 23)
        - Publications, 1961 (Box 339, Folder 1)
        - 60th Anniversary, May 1984 (Box 339, Folder 2)
        - Grant application, 1986-87 (Box 339, Folder 3)
      - Publications
        - When Latticed Windows Opened: Experiences of an American in Turkey by Phoebe Clary as told to Marion O. Robinson, 1969: book and compilation of letters from readers (Box 339, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous, 1914, 1981, n.d. (Box 339, Folder 5)
      - Turkish, Armenian, and Greek press coverage, 1921-33, n.d. (Box 339, Folder 6)
    - Uganda: reports and printed materials, 1982-1988, n.d. (Box 339, Folder 7)